Okay.
Well, it's uh 6:02 on May 18th, 2026.
I'll call this meeting of the Cheyenne
uh City Cheyenne Planning Commission to
order.
Uh will staff please call a roll.
Justin Trip
here.
Daryl Hibbons.
Megan Connor
>> present remotely.
>> Tony Lair
>> here.
>> Bob Mati
>> Amy Hernandez
>> present via Zoom.
>> Boyd Wiggum
>> present.
>> Mr. Chair, we do have a quorum.
>> Okay. Uh, first order of business here
is approval of agenda. Are there any
modifications to the agenda
requested?
Okay, we don't have any minutes. Are
there any disclosures of conflicts of
interest, exparte, communications,
lobbying, etc.
Okay, with that hearing none, will staff
please read them item A into the record?
Item item A, PLTA-26-1,
special use approvals, creation of the
regional entertainment overlay and
development standards for offtrack
betting facilities text amendment.
Okay. Uh, will staff please present the
text amendment? Chair, members of
planning commission, Charles Bloom,
planning and development director. I'm
here to present the proposed text
amendment regarding historic horse
racing in the city limits. The goal of
this ordinance is to align with the new
state statute changes regarding the
licensing provisions of historic horse
racing that are now able to have more
active city governing body
participation. Effectively, if it is
within the city limits, they do have
review authority. Uh what the purpose of
this uh code amendment?
Conor, could you hit that?
Sorry. We'll get the other monitor on
for you all.
The purpose of this code amendment is to
make modifications to the nonconformity
section of our code. That's in article
one. Uh creation of a def creation and
modification of our definitions
regarding historic horse racing. Um
amendments to our special use pro
process that are actually pretty long
overdue. creation of a regional
entertainment overlay district which is
encourage is is uh designed to encourage
uh these uses to go in specific areas of
our community and then creation of
development standards related to
offtrack bedding facilities. Um I do
intend to walk through these uh one by
one and I also do have a a map that I
will show that will sort of demonstrate
what the overlay districts look like. We
do not have the formalized map put
together. I'm still waiting on our GIS
department to get that completed.
Um the amendment text for
non-conformances.
This is essentially a little bit of a
housekeeping item. We're adding the word
legal in front of non-conforming. This
is best practices in land use planning
to call something a legal non-conforming
use if it is in fact a legal
non-conforming use because just
non-conforming on its own does not
clarify that it is legal. So this is uh
basically saying these are legal
non-conforming uses. Item number four is
a new item. Essentially what it allows
is allows the governing body um whenever
they adopt an ordinance and if they
elect to include in that ordinance a
sunset provision or provision where a
use will become obsolete or have a date
certain where it will have to end. this
would allow that to occur and would
allow it to not be classified as a
non-conforming use.
So, how does that work in uh this
scenario of historic horse racing? Let's
say when the council adopts this
ordinance, if they decide to put in the
enabling legislation, the ordinance, a
provision that says that all existing
historic horse racing facilities shall
cease operation by say January 1st of
2027 and seek an approval within with
um in accordance with this code, they
could do so. Um, that is the intent of
this. This specific ordinance does not
establish a sunset date whatsoever. It
just establishes the ability for a
governing body to do that. Um, likewise,
this also would apply to other uses. Say
that they want to change them from
permitted or conditional uses in our in
our development regulations. um it they
could fall into a special use approval
and they could have a sunset requiring a
decision by the governing body.
Um, I should note that all of our
present uh HHR facilities in the city
limits have except for the one located
in the central business district
downtown at Lincolnway and Central have
been approved by the board of
adjustment, which is a board very
similar in composition as yours.
volunteers uncompensated and appointed
um by the governing body upon
recommendation by the mayor.
We do have another cleanup uh portion of
our ordinance which reflects basically
is intended to um help provide clarity
with the overlay district. Essentially
this is the addition of u explanation as
to what happens if there is uncertainty
in the measurement of a zone district
based on a measurement from point A to
point B. In our municipal code right
now, we have um a measurement
requirement for um for sexually oriented
businesses where it says that uh one is
supposed to measure from the wall of the
facility to the property line of a
church or a school. Um there is no um
avenue or direction as to how we make
that interpretation. Likewise, we have
um other descriptors within our
development code which um do note
distance separations. What this does is
it sets a clear practice that's
consistent with best practices that
basically says that if there is a
disagreement on those boundaries, which
we truly don't expect to happen, but if
there is, that disagreement would be
settled um by the person asking the
question um the landowner to uh contract
with a licensed surveyor um and make
that measurement and then we would
update maps accordingly.
The next step, I apologize for the
smaller um font. The next amendment are
some targeted amendments to the review
criteria for the special use approval.
First of all, as you see in the staff
report, um it is a lion share of the
staff report. There are a lot of
different amendments that really reflect
how it works right now. The present
special use permit process was largely
developed prior to the unified
development code and it incorporated
language that was preudc.
For example, the UDC clearly uh calls
the governing body the city council and
then by definition the city council is
defined as governing body. The current
special section actually called the
governing body the governing body. made
sense. Um, but we changed it to reflect
city council to follow the entirety of
the UDC. So, we made some consistency
changes. Um, in addition, we made some
changes that um, aligned it with our
current notification practices to notify
property owners within 300 ft of any
application for special use that's
considered by the governing body. We
added a posted notice provision. So they
have to post a sign on the property
similar to that of a subdivision or a
zoning. And we also added a mailed
notice provision. So those items have
been included in the um special use uh
process and they also have been uh
created in a way to match the other
elements of code. So it's consistent
because it was largely inconsistent.
the previous special or the current
special use approval process really is
limited to uh temporary uses um related
to oil and gas services. So this would
be temporary uses like lay down yards,
oil and oil exploration uh those types
of items. Um we've changed it to make it
more broad that if something is ever
classified as a special use in the use
table, they could utilize this process.
So, it's designed as a one-sizefits-all.
Within the review criteria, we uh did
essentially add two new review criteria.
Um one of them is on top. Um basically,
it is um a catchall that does this
application for special use meet the UDC
review criteria and the development and
design standards. So basically, if it's
in a zone district, does it have the
appropriate landscaping? Does it have
the appropriate building facads, design
materials, all of those items? Um, but
it also states that the governing body
has a flexibility to add additional
conditions for any special use um that
they feel will help mitigate any impacts
that this special use might be might
have on a neighborhood. This could
include items in the case of like oil
and gas support services of additional
landscaping um potentially uh sound
walls that could be installed with an
oil exploration
um business. Um but also in the terms of
an offtrack um HHR facility, this could
include items such as um additional
landscaping, limitations on access, even
looking at limitation of hours of
operation.
Um the the catchall with criteria number
one is that the standards need to be uh
relevant to the specific situation. So
that essentially is the rational nexus
test that it has to be related. It can't
be something that's so extreme and
something that's unrelated.
Um the other item um is number nine. Uh
that is an addition of another criteria
um basically as as to does this use
contribute or contribute to um the
public and provide additional um
benefit. Uh for example, is this a
component of a larger complex that might
serve more than just one isolated uh
group? So, for example, if we look at a
historic horse racing facility that is
standalone on its own in a small
building, that could be one review
criteria where they said, "Okay, we have
this historic horse racing. It's
benefiting that one specialized group."
But if you look at a historic horse
racing facility that could be part of an
overall redevelopment scheme or a
complex where it's catering to different
individuals like maybe a a uh
entertainment center or other types of
options, those could be um benefits that
could be evaluated as part of the review
criteria.
The other items uh were just a couple of
cleanup items within the existing
the existing review criteria um just to
align them with um best practices and to
make sure that they um did match other
elements of how our our code is written.
the proposed overly district and use
table. Um we've done a couple of
amendments to the use table partly uh
cleanup. Number one, we have removed the
columns for planned unit development and
also Capitol Height overlay district and
airport overlay district. Those columns
don't need to be in the use table. Those
are specific to an overlay district.
They are not a base zone district that
should be included in the use table. Um
similarly the um HHR um enabling RE
regional entertainment district is not
one that should be reflected in the use
table. However, in um section uh 5.1.2
of our UDC, that's where we establish
our zone districts. Um, we noticed that
we hadn't clearly established the
earlier overlay district that we adopted
for urban use and we hadn't um clearly
stated the establishment of the uh what
we call the RUCAL. That's a restricted
use control overlay district. That's a
mouthful. Um that is an overlay district
that limits uses based on um
environmental remediation. So in
addition to identifying the re overlay
district as a city zone district um as a
housekeeping item we included the uh
root cow and the urban use overlay
district as well. Essentially for the
historic horse racing uh we um permitted
this as a permitted use in the re
regional entertainment overlay district.
Um, we have allowed it to be considered
as a special use in our CB and CBD zone
district. Apologies for the typo on the
uh, PowerPoint. Um, one of the
requirements in the CB community um,
business and the CBD district is that it
is um, at least 500 ft from specific
uses, which I'll get to a little bit
further down, and that the parcel of
land be adjacent to a minor collector,
principal arterial, um, or a,
uh, major collector or minor arterial
street. Basically, it has to be a uh lot
that is adjacent to a major thoroughare
and not embedded deep into a
neighborhood.
I don't think this is I don't think I'll
be able to log into the web map, so I
might need to switch over
Hey, members of the commission. Sorry
for the delay. This this is a
rudimentary map that I'm pulling up real
quick that sort of explains the overlay
districts. Now, the overlay districts
are four different areas in the
community uh that are envisioned to
allow these the historic horse racing
facilities to essentially land without
having to go through the governing
body's special use permit process.
Essentially, they can walk in if they
meet these criteria and they can apply
for a site plan and then apply for a
building permit. I'll quickly highlight
the four areas of the community that
we're we're looking at.
uh the four areas. This is the High
Plains Road interchange at I25. Um it is
set up in a way that it is 3,000 ft
either side of the center line of the
interchange with Interstate 25. This is
the double roundabout interchange and it
has a qualifier that the parcels must be
adjacent to the interstate
um or adjacent um to
the interstate with the exclusion of any
railroad rightway or stateowned land
right ofway. Essentially what that does
is that skips over the welcome center
and it skips over the uh Burlington
Northern Rail Line that runs on the east
side of Interstate 25.
There is a provision for an absolute
depth of no more than 25 ft from the
right ofway. Um what that's anticipated
to do is to create an entertainment
uh corridor or an entertainment area
that would be located around that
interchange.
Um, in the event of annexation of nearby
parcels of land, if they were to annex
at the time of zoning, they would be
reszoned uh in accordance with this
where they would um have the base zoning
set and then they would also have the
overlay district established
concurrently.
Um, in this in these overlays, there are
there's not a requirement for separation
from churches, schools, or child care
centers um or
or city- owned recreation and athletic
facilities. Um, but they'd be able to
locate anywhere within. That's one of
the areas that is a target area for this
development to occur. Um, another area.
This is West Lincoln Way. The aerial
base map will catch up in a second. This
area is uh properties that are within
300 ft of Lincoln Way between the east
or the western city limits. And this is
pretty much Little America. This is the
older fueling center and uh trace amigos
is over in this direction and the best
western. Um but basically this is within
300 ft of the ride ofway on either side.
So it includes some properties on the
south side as you uh approach Crow
Creek.
Two other areas that are included as
target areas are the 15th Street
corridor, which this is the depot here
on the the far right.
Um it would be the structures that are
located between the alley between
Lincoln Way and 15th um adjacent and
also the Reed Rail Corridor where it is
properties that are adjacent to
the Reed Rail Corridor. I would note
that these blue radius, the rad, the
circles that you see here, the radius um
in the overlay district, those uh do not
um apply. So it could be anywhere along
this area between 23rd and 15th Street.
Um one of the provisions is if it is
located within the read rail section um
that use must take access to the maximum
extent practical essentially um on the
read rail corridor. Um at this time you
know we are presently going through
engineering with uh Burlington Northern
um and they're still trying to determine
where accesses will be. So, in the event
that access is not possible because
there could be a fence, a service road
or an area the public's not welcome,
they would be able to through the
administrative adjustment seek an
alternative where they could access the
adjacent street.
>> Mr. Bloom.
>> Yes. Um, speaking of the blue circles, I
believe the term is radi. But
>> radi, yes, that's what I was looking
for. Thank you.
>> Do I It kind of looks to me like those
would be
the radi around what would otherwise be
the kind of facilities that we're trying
to avoid, the child care centers, the
the schools, churches, etc. Is am I
reading that right?
Chair through to the commission. Yes. in
the re overlay district. Um since these
are targeted areas that are um more
urban or regional in destination,
um those are areas where the radi is is
not deemed to be restrictive. In the
other districts, the community business
and the CBD,
they are. And I'll uh show you how that
looks as we look out this direction.
This this purple area, this is central
business district zoning. This orange
area, this is CB zone district. And
again, the radi here, like for example,
around Holiday Park, this is around a
church, you know, this is the Methodist
church. Um, this is around a state uh
child care. Um, it trims off some of the
property. So, it would only allow the
uses to occur
within areas along Lincoln Way, a small
section of area along um, 17th Street,
18th Street, and then 19th, and it
slowly disappears. all of these areas
here cuz they would require special use
approval by the governing body. It'd
have to go to the governing body for
approval. The areas in the gray hatched
area would not um in evaluating um these
proposals or evaluating how this
interacts. This is East Lincoln away
from this is uh my no this is Logan from
Logan heading west. You're going to have
uh an area roughly between Logan and
then this is Hot Springs where you would
have the ability for parcels that are
fronting this principal arterial or
converse this minor arterial where they
would be eligible for
the use to be um approved by a special
use permit in this area. This is a area
south of Logan. This is Logan. This is
Nation Way right here. This is Lincoln
Way. This is a triangular area. There
are a couple of lots that are not within
the radi of a child care. Um, but they
also are not adjacent to a minor
arterial principal arterial, minor
collector, major collector. So, they
would not be eligible. For example, this
interior lot, this one, this one, and
these ones. So, that's how this this
works. Um, as we uh travel down Lincoln
Way, we have the Cheyenne Plaza where
you have a variety of businesses here in
Cheyenne Plaza that would be eligible
for that that land use.
Um, and then as you go up onto Dell
Range,
uh, very similar as you head out towards
this is Router.
Um, this is west of Converse. you'd be
looking at facilities to be located
along Dell range and also in the area of
of sweetg grass um or sweetgrass and
bluegrass uh circle. I would note that
the uh buffer map the radi uh does need
to be amended by our GIS department
because one of the items that is removed
was childc carees that are located in
shared building complexes. So, for
example, if it's a strip center with a
child care in it, that won't count. Um,
the way it's been set up is it's only
for independent child carees that
um are standalone. And the reason for
that is because if you're looking at a
mixeduse development,
um, for example, you could have a
childcare facility that could elect to
colllocate with one of these larger
facilities. and we didn't want that
provision to fight against the actual
use itself.
Um, apologies that the the other map
wasn't um complete. We've been working
on that with the GIS department and um
there's they're falling behind on that.
Do we have any questions on the overlay
district map before we pop back into the
regular presentation?
Mr. Chair, through you I could you go
back to the I think it was one of the
first ones you showed, but down there at
the uh High Plains Road interchange.
So, and you you then popped up a big
square shape or rectangular shape over
all that with that uh 2500 foot and
3,000 foot. So, right now the only part
of that that's in the city is kind of
the northwest quadrant. Right.
>> Jerry, correct? The on this map through
Commissioner Lar on this map the area
that is highlighted that yellow that is
unincorporated county. So the only area
that is in the city limits right now is
this CB zoned parcel of land that's
located on the northwest portion of that
interchange. It's actually developed
with historic course racing track right
now
or facility right now.
>> Right. So my other question I think the
definition
it gave a certain distance u from the
center line of high of high plains road
and then uh and then it said
perpendicular I think to the interstate
rightway. So eventually high plains road
will be extended to the east.
Is that is that are you taking that into
account or is this all just based on the
existing high plains road alignment?
>> Chair through you to Commissioner
Larair. That's a great question. It took
a little bit of time to make sure we
could uh adequately describe this. How
the measurement is worded in the text is
you start at the center line of High
Plains Road where it intersects the ride
ofway for I25 and it travels 300 ft
either direction following the center
line and then from that rectangle. So
essentially if you had a or a polygon
from here that's 3,000 ft you would
measure 2500 ft perpendicularly off of
the edge of the ride ofway. And if it's
adjacent to the right ofway and within
30 2500 feet, then it would be eligible
for that uh land use. Um on the north
side or the northwesterly side of this,
it's easy because these properties are
less than 2500 ft deep. So anything
across the road loses out on adjacency,
so it's not included. On the east side,
uh that's an area where we have a lot of
unplatted lands. And since it's
unplatted,
um it has the u boundary that is number
one interrupted by in this case another
uh piece of another parcel of land. Um
or uh it's
maxed out by the 2500
foot as measured. So that's how we're
getting that polygon there. And this is
also in the unincorporated county.
And and just as a followup, uh, Mr.
Bloom,
for clarity, if that if that area were
to be annexed into the city and
subdivided, then then that polygon would
shrink to include only those parcels
adjacent to
interstate and high plants. Chair, that
is a a great observation and I point
yourself to an example that exists in
nearby Laram, Wyoming, where there's a
Maverick station located on South Third
Street at Interstate 80. I don't know if
everyone's familiar with that. They have
a sign overlay district, which basically
means that if you have a property that
was within x amount of feet of the
interchange, you were allowed to have a
taller sign, a sign that exceeded their
height limitations by twice the height
limitation and also twice the square
footage. Um, when the Maverick was
developed, it was developed on one large
lot that fell within that uh criteria.
Um, and then after that sign was
constructed, then they subdivided the
land and now Maverick falls outside that
zone and their sign is a non-conforming
sign subject to the non-conforming
um, use provisions. So, um, yes, this
has the ability to shrink if subdivided
um, because of that adjacency
requirement and it's not an uncommon
practice for overlay districts. Um, now
if it were a base zone district, there
would be some concern with a subdivision
of land modifying a base zone district.
>> Mr. Chair, through you.
>> Yes,
>> that reminded me of another one that I
thought of when I was trying to figure
that this piece out. Um,
so I mentioned before eventually High
Plains will be extended to the east
someday. Um, so you say in your
description here, any subsequent
relocation, reconstruction, or
realignment of High Plains Road or
Interstate 25 shall not alter the
boundaries of the overlay district.
Would that include this extension that
I'm talking about, or are you talking
about pieces already built if it were
realigned, for example?
>> Chair, through you to Commissioner
Leairard, it it would not change
anything. Um, the ex Well,
It would not change the boundary. Um if
this roadway were relocated
um as part of construction with High
Plains Road being extended another
direction, we would revisit uh this
specific ordinance and identify if any
necessary changes need to be made in the
way that that overlay district was
described. Uh we if that were to occur,
we'd very likely um end up having a lot
and block description on the other side.
And we could probably more appropriately
make that description via lot and block.
Right, chair? We we do intend to have um
a better map that will be presented with
the governing body and I again apologize
for the rudimentary nature of this but
one thing I would note is in evaluating
all of our current facilities that we
have right now they all do fall within
uh these zones um and within the the
setbacks. I will note that on
uh Persian and
Ridge. Is that where?
Yeah, they they all had
they all fell into
the locations. I
believe we'll have to double We'll
double check that. So, where are we?
That's Persian College.
This is Persian Ridge. I believe there's
a radi issue with this radius that
shouldn't be here. This is the one in
the old Tuskers.
So, this one will be taken out. But most
everything that is um there on our
cursory look that there aren't any um
ones that would be extreme
non-conforming that wouldn't meet that
separation uh from child care park,
church or uh school facility.
Mr. Bloom, why do you think that you're
going to be able to take out that
radius
that captures the old Teskers at the
corner of
of Ridge and Persing. What was it? What
was generating it that it that no longer
applies that that it would come out?
Chair three to the commission. I'm not
exactly certain how the GIS map pulled
that one together because the center of
that radius is right here. You can see
it on the map and there is no use there
other than um that's uh Papa Murphy's
Pizza. There is not a child care in that
location. When we had done our initial
analysis, there is there was no child
care that was within that 500t range.
No child care. There wasn't a church.
There wasn't a a city-owned recreation
facility. There wasn't a school. So,
it's pretty obvious by looking at at
that radius there that there's nothing
there.
>> I have a question. Chair three, next to
Papa Murphy's is a child care.
>> Okay, that's where it came from. And the
the problem the the reason it would be
removed is because it is not in an
independent building because it is in a
strip center. So, it's a single bay of a
multi-unit complex.
That answers that question as to why it
popped up. It did not pop up our initial
drawings.
>> Mr. Chair, are are we asking general
questions about the whole proposal now
or are we still just focused on the map
issues?
>> The map.
>> I I think we're talking about the map
now. I think we've got
further propos uh proposal and then
we'll
try to address the text
and plug the other one in. We'll go
there
and we can go back to that map if we
would need to in the future. Um the
remainder of the presentation uh talks a
little bit about the development
standards um that are being proposed.
Um these development standards are in
line
uh that's the description of the overlay
district.
Um the development standards uh are in
line for properties that are located in
the CB and the CBD zone district.
Essentially, those are the ones that
have that 500t separation from any
elementary school or secondary school, a
child care center operating as a sole
primary use of an of an independent
structure, a place of worship um which
is a church um or a public park or
recreation facility. The measurement um
this describes how it would be made.
This follows our sexually oriented
business measurements um which are
pretty much modeled off of what um is
done as a national standard for
measurements.
Then we have our second qualifier which
is the adjacency requirement for
something to be adjacent to a collector
minor arterial street or principal
street. And we have a qualifier in there
and just more of a notation that states
that just because it's adjacent, this
doesn't indicate that access is required
to those streets because a lot of times
there are access restrictions to those
major roadways um because of traffic and
safety concerns. So they're pushed off
to adjacent streets. So it's just noting
they have to be adjacent but access
isn't there. Similar to what you see on
Tuskers where their access comes off of
the adjacent street. I believe it's
Olive Street and not um the historic
access that used to be on Persing.
Um again in the Reed uh rail overlay
portion of the re zone district, we
wanted to make sure that no one were to
develop this use and simply ignore the
corridor. Um that is not the intent of
the corridor. Um so it was to activate
the corridor. So we have a provision
that requires that um that pedestrian
entrance to be at the corridor and a
process for exceptions.
Um those exceptions are for um issues or
examples where connection can't be made
because people don't have permission to
be there. whether because it's an access
road or worst case scenario, the whole
read rail concept fails and we're not
given direct access to to that read rail
corridor.
Um, and that wraps up the the report.
This would be a sample motion um for you
all. This is our recommended motion, but
if you all wish to go back to the map
for further discussion or wish to
discuss any other details, I'd be more
than happy to um ask Connor to swap out
the computer screens.
With that, are there questions for
staff? Commissioner Lair.
>> Mr. Chair through you, uh if you could
go back to the definition of a gaming
center.
Just want to make sure I had this clear.
You're talking about the use includes
dedicated wagering areas, electronic
terminal, etc.
often featuring ancillary amenities such
as lounges, food and beverage service,
and the onremise sale of alcoholic
beverages. So, you're I think you're
saying all those uses plus the gaming
area included is part of that gaming
center. And I guess
I guess the examples I'm thinking of in
my mind that maybe we could try to
clarify is so the derby club off of
Persian
has
not just a gaming center but the bowling
alley arcade
uh liquor store package liquor store
other things going on there. So would
this gaming center only be defined as
the gaming center part as opposed to
let's say the horse palace out at Swan
Ranch where they just flat say no one
under 20 21 can enter the facility at
all
>> chair through to commissioner. Sorry I
did not have the definition pulled up on
this PowerPoint. Apologies for that. Um
the way that those two facilities are
set up are different. Um the horse
palace, the entirety of the facility is
considered the HHR facility. This is the
one located down south. So that one is
age restricted in its entirety. the one
that is um the Derby Club located on
Persing. Um that one has one entity
which is essentially a a portion of that
building. It's a separate tenant space
that is the only area that is identified
as the historic horse racing facility
and that one is age restricted similarly
as the horse palace. So, at the derby
club, one is able to walk in with the
family through the common areas and they
can peel off to go to one side to go the
bowling with no age restriction or they
can peel off and go into the historic
horse racing facility, but there would
be that age restriction. So, it's only
applying to the um specific use. Now,
the Derby Club is a good example of a
facility that is representative of
review criteria number nine, which it
shows that it's an element um of a
redevelopment or development that's
proposing, you know, a benefit to more
than just the gaming clientele or the
store horse race users. Um that it's uh
creating some additional benefit through
providing other services.
and chair through to Commissioner
Larida. I'm going to um note one more
thing in the definition. We specifically
did not include hotel or motel as a use
accessory to the gaming facility in the
re overlay district specifically because
we wanted
um to make it clear and the expectation
to be that if one was to be developing
lodging facilities or something of a
resort caliber there that they needed to
zone to our CV zone. own district which
would mandate development standards um
in areas that are within the uh re
overlay say high plains it would allow
for this use in our industrial zone
districts that are out there however our
industrial zone districts do not have
design standards for the building so it
could be a metal building with a with a
door and appropriate landscaping but if
you were to build a hotel it wouldn't be
permitted in the industrial zone
districts by right. It'd have to change
over to the CB district to get those
design standards. So that was not an
oversight that was intent.
While we are talking about this,
I I I find a little bit of of the
language here curious and it just it
strikes me as something that's
going to invite trouble down the road
and maybe I'm overly
word smithing. Uh
the second sentence, uh the use includes
dedicated wagering areas, electronic
terminals, and administrative space.
That part makes sense to me. Then we
have the often featuring ancillary
amenities such as lounges,
etc.
I don't know where and why we have the
phrase often featuring other than the
fact I guess it maybe grammatically
flows nicely.
But
are we insisting that that it include
some of these other things in order to
be a gaming center permittable under
this under this stat
this new code?
Or are we saying these things are
optional or they're just illustrative?
At some point, I can imagine somebody
challenging a permit either
whether it's granted or denied
based on I think it strikes me as a
little bit vague the way it's written.
Whether it must include it, may include
it, shall include it.
I don't like it. I don't know how to fix
it right now.
Chair, members of the planning
commission, uh that's a a really good
observation.
This definition was pulled together by
looking at lots of different definitions
ranging from state of Wyoming, state of
Kentucky, Nevada, lots of different
ones. Um perhaps since I'm saying often
featuring it, it can say may feature
accessory uses such as
and that might provide more clarity. Let
me know if that that does and that could
be something you could add to your
motion.
And maybe as a followup as as I
understand the reason for the list of
ancillary amenities was it was crafted
specifically to
not include the logic that you were
speak staff was discussing earlier
chair that is correct.
Yeah, I think we need to tighten this up
to make it clear that it can't include
these other things,
but it needs to be,
I guess, exclusive. If it's not one of
those these things, then it
it can include these items, but only
these items is what we're shooting for.
Correct,
>> T. That is correct,
>> Mr. Commissioner Leair.
>> Yes, Mr.
>> Chair. Through you, I now I'm looking on
the staff report toward the end of page
11, first top of page 12,
uh, amendment text,
5.6.10,
regional entertainment overlay district,
and there's an A, B, C, and D, but I'm
down in D. Permissible uses.
All uses allowed in the underlying
zoning district are allowed as indicated
in table 5-1 notwithstanding table 5-1.
And then it lists a number of other uses
shall be a permitted use within the re
overlay district. So we're saying that
those will now be uses by right if it's
in the overlay district irregardless of
the underlying zone. Is that the intent
of that little section? I guess that
happens.
in enter which page of the staff report
was that on
members of the of the board of the
planning commission. I found that here.
So all uses allowed in the underlying
zone district are allowed as indicated
in table 5-1. So what that means is
if it's shown as a permitted use, it'd
be allowed as a permitted use in that
zone district. Um so for example the
overlay covers CB zone districts. It
also covers um industrial zone districts
and those ones. So it would allow those
uses permitted or conditional however
they're labeled. And the um intent is
that other uses such as
liquor stores, restaurants,
entertainment venues that um um
amusement, recreation, other campgrounds
or recreational vehicle parks are also
permitted. Sorry, I stand corrected.
That's the area where we specifically
excluded hotel um because that would
still require the base zone district to
be changed to a CV district if they
wanted a hotel.
So, Mr. Chair, I guess my specific
question about the way that's written.
Are we saying that for example a
campground in an RV park could be uses
by right the some of these I mean I can
understand out at Swan Ranch perhaps but
the other areas that are in this in the
more developed part of the city we're
not I wouldn't think we'd be adding
those as uses by right
chair uh through you to commissioner
leard that is correct the way that's
worded um those would be allowed if you
wish to amend any of those uses is out
like campground or recreational vehicle
park. You could do so in your motion.
>> Mr. Chair, if I may, Conor Way Planning
and Development Department. So, even if
those uses are allowed, campgrounds have
specific regulations they still need to
meet. So, to fit a campground like along
the Reed Rail,
I don't know if they could actually meet
all the requirements in our campground
regulations to do so. So that's also
something to consider is yes, even
though it might allow those now as a use
by right, there are other requirements,
just by being a use by right, doesn't
mean you can meet all the other
requirements for that area. So
while yes, staff is proposing to allow
those as a use by right maybe along Reed
Rail,
finding a property that can meet all the
standards that we now have for
campgrounds in the UDC might be very
difficult.
Along those same lines,
as I read this, I don't see how some of
these uses that elsewhere would be
treated as conditional in whatever zone
district district they're permitted.
I I don't see how that is preserved
here.
if they are a use by right because in my
mind a use by right and a conditional
use are mutually exclusive
and I'm thinking specifically of liquor
stores bars as being the type of thing
that might be more conditional and it
doesn't look like there's anything
conditional here if they're in the
re overlay
>> chair members of the planning commission
um the the way this is word for
permissible uses. Um, it does say as
indicated in table 5-1, which I guess if
it's not on the list of additional
items,
um, it would retain how it's listed in
the table. So, for example, if it's not
in the overlay district,
it would, um, require that it be
a conditional use. However,
um as written, you all are correct that
if it's in the re overlay,
um it is now listed as a permitted use
and if it were a conditional use, it
would be permitted and that conditional
use provision would be gone.
Chair, members of the commission, for
clarification, in the CB district, uh
bars and liquor stores and those items
are conditional uses. Um we've had a
handful of those who have gone through
the board of adjustment for approval. Um
one of those was the liquor store at the
Derby Club. Um there's another one that
I can recall the like the Maverick up on
North Yellowstone. The um Big D out on
uh technically North Gley Highway, which
is that segment between Fox Farm Road
and Interstate 80. That's North Gley
Highway.
Fun fact. Um um and also at Swan Ranch
uh the the historic horse racing
facility there, there's a conditional
use uh for their uh liquor sales because
that is zone CB as well. um with the way
that this um re overlay district is
crafted, the conditional use approval
for the historic race horse racing at
Swan Ranch would not be required for
that liquor license element. Um it would
be able to be a byite use uh similar to
historic horse racing as well as those
properties that are located um along the
Reed Rail and also along uh West Lincoln
Way and portions of 15th Street.
I imagine we'll want to get back to
that.
I've got a couple three questions.
What is the necessity of of including
the sunset of non-conforming uses of
legal non-conforming uses to this or is
it just one of the things we're catching
along the way?
chair, members of the commission. Um the
reason for that is in the event that the
governing body wishes to essentially put
a sunset on, for example, the historic
horse racing when they adopt the
ordinance. Right now, the
locationational
um review was based on the county
commissioners making that decision and
then the city having to go through and
have an approval by the board of
adjustment where the governing body did
not uh precisely weigh in on that
location. So in the event that they wish
to bring them all back to the table
essentially for um re-evaluation
based on their historical operations,
this would give the governing body the
ability to do so.
But as I understand this, this sunset of
non-conforming uses is going to apply to
all the other non-conforming uses that
currently exist,
including the ones that just got maybe
annexed in or or is this going to be I
didn't see how it was specifically
confined to applying to
gaming facilities. ities and chair
that's a great observation. I'll I'll
further expand on on this.
Um the intent is that if there is a
action by the governing body to change
what is currently a conditional use or a
permitted use, anything in the use table
today to a special use. to something
that has an S on it, which right now the
only things that would have an S on it
if approved um today, like if approved
through this process, would be the uh
gaming center
and also the oil and gas support
services in the HI district. Um
right now uh if they were to say want to
change let's use childc cares as an
example
uh to a special use
if in that enabling ordinance the one
where they make that change they they
could elect to put a sunset date in
there. It doesn't mandate that they have
to. It just gives them the option that
they could if it's something that they
wish to do.
Thank you.
It strikes me that this is written so
that this disordant this
code change
would apply without weaking
to full-on casinos if if the state
legislature would decide that that's
where Wyoming was headed. Do I
understand that correctly or was that an
intent or
chair, members of the planning
commission, um the intent was that this
was very isolated and limited to the
historic horse racing and it did not
apply to general casino type of
operations. Um, we would be able to see
a casino coming pretty pretty reasonably
well because it would require
legislative action and it may actually
require more um than legislative action
due to um agreements uh with our local
tribal agencies
regarding gambling.
>> Okay. But just for our own protection
though,
I I know what the intent was. But am I
wrong in observing that it seems like
this could apply to casinos? Meaning
that a casino would not pop up someplace
other than one of the places permitted
here. Are we safe there? That would be a
goal in my mind.
>> Chair, members of the planning
commission, um the way we've crafted it,
we're confident that this cannot apply
to casinos.
like the typical casino you would see in
Reno or Las Vegas. Um the definition
clearly states is for um the historic
horse racing and paramutual betting, you
know, based off of the results of live
horse racing.
And also it exempts um any
interpretation that it would um apply to
skill-based games, which are um ones
that you might see in banks of seven at
like a local tavern. Um, also things
where you might place a coin in and the
coins drop and you can catch coins. Um,
or the claw machines. Those are all
considered skill-based um, games. So, we
made sure it didn't apply to facilities
that have the um, statutory allowance
for those, which I believe is around
seven.
Is your chair through you? What? Go
ahead.
So just a big picture question
clarification. So this these this
so-called special use approval is
strictly goes directly to the governing
body. It gets gets applied for and goes
directly to the governing body. It
doesn't have any action by either the
planning commission or the board of
adjustment like unlike say the
conditional uses
and chair members of the commission that
is correct. This would go directly to
the governing body for the decision.
Are there any questions from Zoomland? I
guess while we're here and reviewing. I
know we've got two members of the
commission that are attending via Zoom
and I don't want to overlook them.
>> I have no questions.
>> Uh no questions, Mr. Chairman.
Okay. Thank you,
Mr. Bloom. I had kind of a question that
surfaced in an earlier discussion, too.
We were talking about the distinction
between
the facility that's
in the building I still think is the
think of as old McGomery Wards, I think,
Derby Club. I think I'm not an expert on
exactly which company has which location
around town. They're not places I
frequent. Um versus the one down at Swan
Ranch and and we were discussing what
was defined as as
governing here. Do we need to tighten up
the language to be able to distinguish
which gaming facilities people can walk
into with kids? If the kids are going to
go do something else, restaurant
bowling, etc., or not. I'm a little
concerned that both things can happen.
And I'm not entirely certain
whether we're clear on what we're
dealing with here or if we or if we need
to be or if it's up to the discretion of
the owner
and chair, members of the planning
commission, I don't believe we need to
make that call here at the unified
development code level. I believe that
the age restrictions are put in place by
the state licensing agency, the the ones
who uh facilitate the license. I mean
they they are the ones who um put that
restriction in place.
Can you please pull up the map
or is anybody else want to talk about
the text before we go to the map?
And I guess where I'm headed here is
the number of
of radi
that the exemption under the re overlay
is going to grant an exemption to along
the reed avenue corridor. It looks like
there's a lot of what I would call
sensitive locations that we're carving
out. And
I wonder whether or not that's
whether we want to do that given how
close Reed Avenue is to kind of the
you know everything from Catholic school
to to other things
or or is that something that
specifically the governing body has has
expressed a desire for?
Chair members, the commission, my
computer has has died. Um, it spent too
much time off plug today because of a
extended public services committee
meeting hasn't had time to recharge. Um,
at this time, uh, when it came to the
radi and looking at the urban fabric, we
recognize that in our downtown areas
that those are urban areas with a
variety of uses. Um so that's why we as
staff when we were asked to um look into
this we um based identify that this is a
mixeduse area which is super dense,
super walkable. It's a variety of
different uses and as a carrot to try to
encourage develop in these areas that
are lightly developed. um we essentially
recommended removing those restrictions.
Um notably because in urban fabrics law
those restrictions aren't expected and
that that's the whole purpose behind it.
It really is just a um
idea to encourage
I don't know if it's a word urbanity.
I like the term urbanity. Is there a
best practice on on that we need to be
aware of
as we're thinking about these places
where we're granting the re exemption
through the overlay
>> chair members of commission I didn't
look into whether or not that was best
practices I I looked into how did it fit
into our community and in my opinion it
appeared that it looked like it would
fit fit in
Any
other questions, comments,
desires for amendments?
Is there a timeline that the city
council is looking for this
or is this something where we could ask
for a a repeat with some tweaks in
language
as opposed to trying to amend on the fly
here
and chair? Members of the planning
commission, we would like to try to move
this forward with an introduction at our
May uh the 28th meeting. I believe
that's the Tuesday after Memorial Day
26th. Um and then have it wrapped up by
the end of July, which would have it
effective um in parallel with state
statue. So there really isn't much room
for postponement.
Um, but you're more than welcome to
suggest um amendments and we can try to
fine-tune those amendments here, but you
always do have the power to to postpone.
However, it could um create some delays
in
council um adoption of the final
ordinance.
Uh, Commissioner
>> Chair throughu I do have a question and
this is just being new I guess to this
language and and looking I understand
there probably isn't a regulation
requirement through state statute but
what is generally for 500 ft what
establish that why why do we do 500 feet
from schools and why isn't it larger
than that and then I have one followup
after you answer that one
>> chair members of the commission to
commissioner trip. Um the 500 ft was a
was a measurement that was picked. We
evaluated 1,000 ft and 1,000 ft
essentially uh excluded most every
property zone CB. It really narrowed it
down to something that wasn't uh
reasonable. 500 ft. What that represents
is I mean our downtown area in our urban
core, it's just um over a block and a
half. So it almost gives people about a
almost a twob block radius from these
uses and that's really where it where it
came down down from. It was a number
that was selected.
Thank you. And chair three, my second
question is as you discussed and I I
caught on quickly what you meant cuz
Papa Murphy's there is a child care
right next to there but it's not the
sole primary use. There's another
building in there. What why do we only
consider for child care
unless it's own building? Because my
concern would be say Papa Murphy's went
out of business and somebody bought
bought that building and converted in
and you have
track you know you have gambling right
next door to a child care facility. Why
do we only say in a soul building
and chair members of the commissioner
and commissioner trip? Um the reason for
that was primarily in the event that you
had a mix of uses in a complex um that
we didn't want someone to essentially
shoot themselves in their in their own
foot by introducing a childcare type of
arrangement um that could complement the
complex. Um in some areas you might have
a facility that has that's larger that
may have child care services or a
daycare or some type of learning
institution that that holds that
license. Um, and that could be a benefit
to a family or a that's coming in where
maybe one grouping wants to go into the
age restricted for this offtrack bedding
um, and they'd like to have child care
for their for their uh, child to either
enhance their learning or just to be
watched. That was the the way we framed
it.
>> Thank you.
Chair, if I may, I do believe that the
concerns that I that I heard from you
all were regarding the definition um
making sure we tightened that language
down. Um and what was the other concern?
So, I think both of those were able to
be adequately addressed for us to be
able to move forward with this item to
bring to the governing body.
>> M Mr. chair through you to director
Bloom. I I don't know if this is the one
you're thinking of specifically, but I
my my my
main heartburn I think was with this
permissible uses in the re overlay
u new section and the fact that we've
added a list of u
uh use by rights to the under these
underlying zoning districts. And I I'm
if I had to make a motion now, I would
probably want to amend it to not include
that say the second sentence there, not
not have any special use by rights just
because it's in this overlay district. I
think letting the gaming facility be
there is enough, but and they should go
through the hoops for the rest of it is
my thought.
>> Okay. Was that what what staff was
thinking of as being the other one? Does
that sound familiar?
>> Yes, that that does sound familiar. And
and chair, members of the commission,
Commissioner Leard, if if I may just um
add the reason that was included was we
were looking for uses that could be
considered common um for regional
entertainment. Um and primarily the
number one one the number one one that
accommodated these these gaming centers
was the alcohol um license, the liquor
sales, those type of things. Um so that
was one that we had initially included
and then we expanded it just slightly to
include the other uses you see which
were um the campgrounds, the
recreational vehicle park, those types
of items. So, um, if you do look at
recommending that that be removed, um,
we just ask that you kind of look at it
in in two parts. Number one, is it the
entirety of the sentence? Um, or is it
just maybe, uh, one of those, um, uses,
but either way, we're okay with
forwarding whatever your recommendation
is to the governing body.
Okay. Thank you. Any other questions for
staff before I open it up for public
comment? Anything from Zoomland
from the commissioners?
Okay, with that, I'll open this up for
public comment. Is there anybody here
from the public who wishes to speak?
Okay, please state your name and address
for the record, sir.
>> Dr. Mark Renie, Cheyenne City Council.
Um, Mr. Chairman, members of the
committee, thank you.
And
the impetus for for this ordinance
change arose a couple years ago. Um, I
along with the executive directors for
Wyoming Association Municipalities and
WCC Wyoming County Commissioners
Association
worked with an interim committee in the
summer of 2024. Worked with the bill
trying to get through the legislature
in 2025.
Thought we had a good bill that
everybody agreed on, but it died in the
end. So after that um
my if you recall a couple little while
prior to that we had seemed like we got
a significant influx of HHR venues in
the community.
And what we learned in doing that
obvious was that the city council had no
control generally over what where they
went and how many we had. that was
determined the licenses were given by
the state gaming commission and state
statute at that time um gave permission
for locations to go just through the
county commission.
So um and yet it was city council that
seemed to get all the grief from the
from the citizens because you know they
we were all getting emails and calls by
how many of these are we going to have?
Why aren't you regulating them? Why
aren't you controlling them? and we kept
saying, "We have no control. The state's
given us no control. It all goes through
the county commission." Um,
and we had um seven of the at the time
there were nine HHR venues in the
county. Seven of them were within the
city of Cheyenne. And of those seven,
only one um was zoned properly and that
is the one in the central business
district. Um and again so as a result in
talking to my colleagues and our
frustrations when our attempt to give
the city some control in the dur through
the legislature
um failed. Then I approached Charles and
said look my colleagues and I would like
to regulate this as much as we can
through zoning and we would like it. We
are fine. There are four areas that we
think work where we'd like to promote
development and see them go. And those
are Reed Avenue corridor, 15th Street,
West Lincoln Way, and the High Plains
interchange. Any place outside of that,
we want them to come through us. The
other problem was when it went through
the board of adjustments, that's not an
elected board. It's not
I know they're responsive to the
citizensry but not like I think that we
are when we have to stand for election
every four years.
So um so the request um in talking with
my colleagues on the council I went to
Charles said look we don't mind we would
like to see development in these four
areas and if allowing HHR to go there as
a use by right works helps develop those
areas we're fine with that outside the
city we no longer or outside of those
four areas we no longer want it going to
the board of adjustments we want it to
come directly to us And so as a result
that requires a special use permit um in
order to kind of take care of the four
areas that we were interested in. We had
to do the overlay districts. So this is
what and so Charles and staff I mean
every now and then they touch base with
me but um this is what they've been
working on for a year now and trying to
get all the parts to work together. This
is what's come out of it. and they also
as as he's told you has also used the
opportunity to change some deficiencies
that we've had in our in our zoning
ordinances. So, um that's where the
incentive came from. That's where, you
know, I know ch Mr. Chairman, you asked
about Reed Avenue. That was one of the
specific areas that the council wanted
to promote some development. Um but this
is how it started out. These were our
initial requests and this is what you
have. So I would hope that you know if
you tweak it a little bit I'm fine with
that but in the end I hope you can
support it. Thank you.
>> And if you have any questions I'd be
happy to answer.
>> Maybe this is an exception to our
protocol but are there any questions of
the speaker from the commission?
Yeah. Okay. Okay. Well, thank you.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Um, I understand there are members of
the public who wish to speak on this
online.
>> Mr. Chair, possibly. Um, if any member
online would like to speak, please use
the raise hand feature and I can give
you permission.
Are there any members of the public who
wish to speak online?
Hearing
none, public comment is now closed.
With that, I I think I'm looking for a
motion from the commission.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to recommend the
governing body approve text amendments
to the unified development code amending
UDC sections 1.3.11
nonconforming
nonconformities
1 1.4.4
definitions
1.4.5
in interpretation of zoning map 2.2.7
special use approval 5.1.2 2 zoning
districts established and 5.1.4
use table and creating 5.6.10
regional entertainment
uh re overlay district and 5.7.13
gaming center development standards as
outlined in this staff report and
recommended by staff noting the
amendments meet the review criteria of
UDC 2.4.1.D.
I think I got all the lines in there.
>> Okay, thank you. It's been moved. Do I
have a second?
>> Second.
>> It's been seconded by Commissioner
Leair.
Um discussion by the commission or
proposed amendments to the motion.
>> Mr. Chair.
>> Uh, Commissioner Leair,
>> I would propose to amend the motion to
exclude
under the
amended text 5.6.10D
permissible uses
to exclude the
bars and liquor stores in that list of
newly permitted uses.
>> Okay, I'll take your proposal as a
motion to amend.
Do we have a second to the to the motion
to amend?
And can you remind
it looks like Commissioner Trip is
looking for that
Uh, if you're in the staff report, it's
the bottom of page 11, top of page 12.
Your permission uses.
Do I have a second for discussion?
>> I'll second that.
>> Okay. Thank you. It's been the motion to
amend has been seconded by Commissioner
Trip. Now we can talk about it. Any
members of the commission want to talk
about
removing the bars and the liquor stores
from the list of
what will be now uses by right
um in the regional overlay district
if established as proposed.
Commissioner Lar.
>> Mr. chair, just to support my motion, uh
the uh
I think for the most part in the table
now, bars and liquor stores are only the
only place they're per use by ride is in
the central business district
essentially. And so it seems like in
that code, the spirit of the code is
that those are pretty big deals that we
want to go through a bit of a process to
consider where they're going to go at.
And I I'm just trying to stay in the
flavor of that. To to be honest, it sort
of goes against my libertarian instincts
a little bit because I'm I'm not I'm not
that crazy about the fact that uh liquor
license are as tightly controlled in
this state as they are. But
nevertheless, uh the code is what it is
and they're only now
uh there we go through a process for
everywhere except the central business
district for those.
>> Okay. Thank you. Any other comment? Any
other discussion?
Any more items on this list that that
we should discuss including in in the
amendment?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Could I ask
staff a question?
>> I go ahead motion.
So
obviously part of these proposed
um the four proposed areas are in the
central business district and then I
think part of the Reed Avenue corridor
is not. Is that correct? Uh but it's in
the urban overlay.
Is that is that correct? And if so
would the would the bars and liquor
stores be a permitted use there as well?
>> And chair members of the commission. Um,
good question. In the urban use overlay
district, the bars and liquor stores
will still fall to the base zone
district, which in that UYU district, it
is MUB, mixeduse business. So, they
would still require a conditional use
approval. For example, um, Westp for
example, they had a conditional use
approval, they still would have a
conditional use approval. Uh, the
railspur, same situation. They would any
new business that meets the qualifiers
of the re overlay district adjacent to
Reed Rail, say the Wyoming Tribune Eagle
building, they would also require um a
uh conditional use approval for that bar
or liquor store uh approval
as as proposed with that motion. And if
this were to not pass.
Okay. Any other comment? Any other
discussion?
Hearing none. Um, as a reminder, uh, I'm
going to call for a roll call vote. And
as a reminder, this is a vote on on the
proposed amendment to remove
bars and liquor stores from the list of
uh
allowed uses by right
uh in the re overlay district.
Will staff please call roll.
>> Amy Hernandez. No
>> Justin Trip.
>> Yes.
>> Bob Mati.
>> No.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Yes.
>> Megan Connor.
>> No.
>> Mr. Chair, that amendment fails.
Okay. Thank you.
Any other further discussion?
uh proposed amendments to
to the proposed code. Commissioner Trip.
>> Yes, Chairman. I have a proposed
amendment
on page 12 of the staff report. So, it'
be under um 5.73
gaming centers section A. So, the
language where it says child care center
operating as sole primary use of
independent structure. I would like to
make amendment that says child care
center at time of application.
Okay, we've got a motion to amend. Do we
have a second to the proposed amendment?
>> Second.
Okay,
>> thank you. Is that Commissioner Connor?
For the record, who who who seconded the
the amendment, please?
>> This is Commissioner Connor. I seconded
that.
>> Okay. Thank you.
It's been moved and seconded. Any
discussion? Uh would Commissioner Trip
like to explain his amendment?
>> Yes. My my amendment would is based on
this child care center at time of
application would make it so if there's
a child care in that area that would
apply to that 500 ft rule. So it
wouldn't be the sole building. So my
example would be you you have across the
street. So back to Papa Murphy's there's
a child care right next to it. Say
there's a gaming facility going to open
up within that 500. There's still a
child care facility there. though it's
in an independent not at an independent
building I still have concerns on that.
So that's the basis of that amendment.
>> Okay. Thank you. Further discussion from
the commission
>> and Mr. Chair just to clarify maybe from
Commissioner Trip. So we're not just
adding the saying at the time of
application but we're striking the words
operating as the sole primary use of
structure.
>> Yes, I should have probably clarified
that better. We would strike the words
operating as a sole primary use as an
independent structure. So it would read
child care center at time of application
because you want to be fair because say
there isn't a child care there and
somebody's going through permits and
they're already in it and some then
somebody opens the child care with them
that wouldn't be fair either. So at the
time of application
>> okay thank you.
Any other further discussion from the
commission on the proposed amendment
commissioners on Zoomland?
Hearing none, it's been moved and
seconded. Will staff please call role on
the amendment to revise the language
around
presence of a child care center even if
it's in a building with other other
uses.
Megan Connor
>> Megan Connor.
>> Hi
>> Justin Trip.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Yes.
>> Amy Hernandez.
Tony Alert.
>> No,
>> Mr. Chair, that amendment passes.
>> Okay, thank you. And Commissioner Trip,
be sure to touch your your button so we
can rec record your vote.
Okay, we've got that amendment passes.
Any other discussion? Any other proposed
amendments? I don't think I can offer an
amendment uh to tweak the language
around uh other uses such as if anybody
else is interested in that issue, this
would be the time to take it up.
Further discussion,
further amendments
hearing none.
Uh will staff please call roll on the
the motion to approve as amended.
Just wanted to take note real quick of
on my paper that's as amended. Um so
back on the main motion, uh Bob Mati,
>> yes.
>> Justin Trip,
>> yes. Amy Hernandez,
>> I
>> Tony Lair,
>> yes.
>> Megan Connor,
>> no.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Will staff please read item B into the
record?
Item B,
P or PLTA-26-2
carports text.
>> Okay. Will staff please
offer offer its report.
Chair, members of the commission
counterweight, planning and development
department.
All right. So the text amendment before
you has to do with carports um as the
name says. So this text amendment was
actually brought forward. Um staff was
asked to look at it by a council member.
Um I will note also that there's a lot
of public that we get constant calls
about when it comes to carports. Um, I
can probably safely say within the past
month, I've had at least a dozen, two
dozen phone calls
that basically deal with what this text
amendment is. Um,
so starting out with this uh with
carports, a little bit of background.
CarPorts are accessory buildings under
current code. They're considered
accessory buildings, reviewed as
accessory buildings.
What that means when you follow
accessory building code is one, you're
allowed two accessory buildings on your
property.
Um, accessory building square footage is
basically dictated by how big your lot
is and the size of your house. So, an
accessory building can't be larger than
your house. Can only be 15% or the total
of both accessory buildings can only be
15% of the square footage of your lot.
Additionally, when it comes to setbacks,
accessory buildings are not allowed to
be within your front yard. They have to
be 10 feet behind the front of the
house. So, whatever the closest front
wall of the house is to the basically
your front property line, you measure 10
ft behind that before you can even put
an accessory building.
That does not allow a carport on your
front driveway.
So, under current code, any carport you
see in the community where it's on a
front driveway is illegal. It is a
zoning violation. Should not be there.
Probably doesn't even have a building
permit.
Um,
on corner lots, basically carports, if
you want to have it face the side street
and be put on a driveway there, also
cannot be there. Accessory buildings are
required to be 25 ft from your side
property line if it has vehicular access
facing that side street. So again, any
carport that's on the side property line
or side street for a corner lot, if it's
there currently, it is also a zoning
violation.
Not a lot of people know this uh
throughout the community. We also don't
get a lot of complaints. Um most of the
complaints I'm getting are why don't you
allow me to have this on my front
driveway?
Um so this was brought to us um by a
council member to look into it. And that
is basically the basis of this text
amendment is to allow them uh to be on
front driveways. So some of the things
we had to look at for changing this um
is basically making making carports not
accessory buildings or considered
accessory buildings. Um so one of two of
the things we have to kind of amend in
here are the definitions. So with
building accessory, we did add a line in
there so that carport accessory to
residential uses on lots that do not
require site plan review uh shall be
regulated exclusively
under the standards of section 589 which
is the new section for carports uh and
shall not be considered an accessory
building for the purpose of this code.
And then we did give carport a specific
definition in here just so it has one.
So a carport is an accessory building or
yeah it's still and I know in the
definition it says it's an accessory
building but um it's to offer limited
protection to vehicles from the elements
and the structure may be freestanding or
attached to another structure.
So kind of looking again this kind of
goes back to what I was talking about
when it comes to current code and
proposed code.
Um, with current code, as I mentioned,
uh, they are considered accessory
buildings. They need to be 10 ft behind
the front of a principal building.
Corner lots, their side step bags 25 ft.
And they are limited, uh, you are
limited to two accessory buildings
total. So, if you have a detached garage
and a shed,
those are your accessory buildings. You
can't add another accessory building.
Um, so if we didn't make it where
carports weren't accessory buildings and
just kind of put in standards to allow
them in the front, if somebody had a
garage, detached garage in a shed, you
still can't put that carport basically
on your front driveway if it was still
considered an accessory building.
uh accessory buildings are limited on
the the square footage as I mentioned
the 15% of your lot area and then also
um
basically the size of your house
and then under current code technically
any accessory building can be enclosed
um with the proposed amendments uh kind
of the regulations that we're proposing
which is in the staff report it's under
that 589 uh carport section
Uh,
basically you would be allowed to have
them on your front driveway. Um,
they would need to be a minimum of 2 ft
from the property line that's along that
front street.
And then the director may reduce that
setback down to zero through
administrative adjustment upon finding
that the carport will not interfere uh
with a current or future public
sidewalk.
The reason we added that in there that
it could be reduced to zero is in some
cases you do actually have a right ofway
that is extremely large where you might
have an attached sidewalk and then
another 10 ft of right of way before you
hit the property line.
So in cases like that where we look at
it you could actually get your set your
setback on the front basically reduced
to zero for that carport. Um,
otherwise the minimum is 2 ft from that
front property length, but ultimately
this does allow them on front driveways.
On corner lots, um, it would be the same
thing. If you have a driveway that faces
the side street, you can put a carport.
It can be within two feet of that side
property line. And again, depending on
uh conditions of the area, could be
reduced to zero.
for side and rear setbacks. They'll just
conform to accessory building setback
standards for each zone district. So,
you can still put them in your backyard.
It's not this isn't creating anything
where it says you can't have a carport
that's alley loaded or anything like
that. Um
they basically they just follow the
setbacks for normal accessory buildings
in the backyard, but they're not
considered accessory buildings for the
number of accessory buildings you can
have.
We did end up limiting these to one
carport port uh one carport per dwelling
unit. Um so single family home you can
have a single carport can be your front
driveway could be um basically at the
back of the property off the alley
wherever you choose to put it. Um,
we cap them at 600 square ft.
And then we do have within here uh
provisions. So if you did want an
additional carport or you did want a
larger carport or something of that
nature, it can go to the board of
adjustment for a conditional use. Um,
that's similar to what we do with
accessory buildings. Accessory
buildings, if you want a larger
accessory building, you want more than
two accessory buildings, you go to the
board of adjustment basically for a
conditional use. it gets reviewed and
board of adjustment can approve um kind
of those changes and allowance to have
additional or extra
for properties that and if you noticed I
had it per dwelling unit. So if a
property does have like a duplex, a flat
overflat duplex, they can technically
have two carports. You have two dwelling
units. Same thing if you have a
accessory dwelling unit, technically
have two dwelling units, you can have an
additional carport. Um
we also put in here that carports um
no more than two sides of a carport may
be enclosed in any manner. Um on any
side where the enclosure is provided,
the lower 50% of the vertical wall
facade shall remain open and
unobstructed
in the full horizontal extent of the
facade.
The reason for putting this in there is
so that we don't start getting these
tunnels. Um you can probably find some
of these throughout the community. You
start getting people enclosing the sides
completely. Throw it up against the
garage. Now you got three sides
enclosed. it starts to fill in with a
lot of things other than just cars. Um,
that's not the intent of allowing these
in the front. These are meant for the
people who are looking to protect their
vehicles, not come extra storage space
for everybody's junk. Um,
so that's why we have it at the 50%
enclosure on the sides. It still keeps
it open. Um, it basically makes it so
it's less likely to become more of a a
new garage addition and keeps it as just
what it was meant for for protecting the
vehicles.
And um, it also allows for just
enforcement of if there's any nuisances
for junk and trash and things of that
nature.
So you can see definitely different
carports that are already out there
throughout the community.
Um
noting the one on the left, it's
obviously in the front of the house.
That one would become conforming uh most
likely with these regulations.
The upper one on the right,
technically that is a carport that comes
off the front of the house. Yes, it is
integrated into the house. That's a much
nicer carport, but that is a carport.
Um, as you can see, the bottom part is
actually enclosed. We do actually have
that within that standard I was reading
from earlier. Um, if somebody does start
to basically enclose the bottom 50%,
it does have to have design standards
where it matches um, basically the
house.
I do believe actually that one in the
top, if I measured correctly, I think
that might actually already meet setback
requirements to be there. I wanted to
throw that in there though to show
different kind of options of what a
front carport could look like.
And then the one on the bottom um as you
can see that's basically at a zero foot
uh setback.
These are all different options of what
could happen um or what it could look
like with the proposed text amendment.
again, uh, this text amendment being
brought forward from a council member
and then as I also said, I have probably
had dozens of phone calls even just in
the last month of basically what is up
on the screen of what people want to do.
Um, rarely do I get phone calls of
complaints about the illegal ones that
are already out there.
Um, it's mostly people calling and
saying, "I want to put a carport on my
property. This is where I want to put
it." Minute they tell me it's on their
front driveway, I have to tell them no.
And they're usually not very happy with
me at that point. Um, then they ask,
"Well, how can I go about doing so?" And
that requires variances. Have to go to
board of adjustment. Isn't guaranteed
you'll get a variance.
Um, so
staff kind of looked at this as it seems
that a lot of the community is okay with
having carports on the front driveway.
Uh whether they be metal carports. I
actually had a gentleman who came in
last week and wanted to
do similar to actually the one in the
upper right. He wanted to do an
extension off the front of his garage um
and make it match his house. Again, I
had to tell him unfortunately with our
current regulations, you can't do that.
Um, but I did tell him there was a text
amendment coming up. So, if he did want
to come support it, he definitely could.
Um,
so with that,
staff does recommend approval of the
text amendment. Um, I'm available for
any questions.
>> Okay. Thank you. I I guess my first
question is how in the world did we wind
up in a world that the picture that was
in the top right was regulated as a
carport?
It just it it strikes me as what I'd
expected, a really nice restaurant or
something. Um
I did have a couple of
thoughts.
Uh, one in our definition of what a
carport is,
we start off calling it an accessory
building after saying that it's not.
>> Surely there's a synonym we could use
for building that work in there, an
accessory device, an accessory
structure.
>> Mr. Actually, just gonna say accessory.
We could change it to instead of
building structure,
>> accessory structure
>> because otherwise I think somebody could
slice and dice. Again, that makes me a
little nervous in terms of
somebody complaining and saying this is
vague or nonsensical or just undermine
credibility of our process.
Second,
is there any way we could tweak this?
So, and one of the pictures captured it
so that
you know, yeah, we're talking about
setbacks from the front lot line or from
lot lines or things like that. Two feet,
which seems inconsequential to me. Two
feet might as well be zero.
Um, but is there any way to have the set
back be a little bit further from
a sidewalk so that it would be it has to
be set back X from the front lot line
and X from the edge of any sidewalk,
future sidewalk, something like that. So
that it's not right up against the
pedestrian way.
And then finally, I was kind of looking
for words, doing a word search in the
proposed ordinance.
What do we have to ensure that these
things don't blow away? Because I'm
envisioning their utility is the reason
we want them.
Yeah, there's the sun, but we have hail
and we have wind.
Is that something that should be
included in in
mr
>> regulation? If I could interject because
I had the same question and made myself
a note as I was reviewing this and then
I think almost at the very end of the
proposed new section
uh that says a building permits
required. I'm presuming that in the
building permit process they're going to
make sure it's adequately anchored and
then an inspection will make sure that
it it's built that way. So I don't know
that we need to address that spec. I
don't know how we would address it any
better in the code.
Mr. Chair through you. So
with car with any structure on a
property if it's over 200 square feet it
does require a building permit. And I
know when it comes to carports, one of
the things that they look for is how is
this being anchored? Um, so that is
actually a requirement with building
code to anchor these structures
properly.
Okay. Thank you. Other questions for for
staff from the commission?
>> Mr. Chairman, I had a question on how
did you settle on 600 square feet,
>> Mr. Tru? So,
when we looked at the square footage,
um, it's kind of taking a look at what
do we allow for accessory buildings
right now when it comes to like detached
garages or what's a typical detached
garage you're finding. Um,
in most cases, if somebody is looking at
two-car garages, things like that
nature, you're getting close to that 600
square foot.
um not all the time, but
you can get to 600, especially if it's a
20 by 30. Right there, you've got your
600 ft. Um
and with a two-car garage, that's
probably around what you're looking at.
Uh in most cases, I always see a garage
being at least 20 ft wide. Um and then
you got to kind of consider the depth of
most vehicles nowadays.
Now that square footage could be taken
into various accounts. It doesn't have
to be 20 by 30 can do anything to meet
that. Um but also I have seen carports
where people want them for their
campers.
Those can get awfully big. Uh depending
on the size of the camper. Um, so that's
kind of how we looked at the square
footage and just we felt that 600 was
high enough to give people the option,
uh, but not s going too crazy where you
might get a carport that is actually
somehow larger than the house in some
cases or the footprint of the house
because that's how accessory buildings
work is you can't have a footprint for
your accessory building bigger than the
footprint of the house. Um,
so it's still kind of keeping the
building.
I know it's not an accessory building,
but accessory to the house.
>> But you said 25 by 30 that
>> Well, 20 20 by
>> 20 by 30.
>> Yep.
>> Um,
the the carport in that lower right hand
corner, is that 600? Would that meet the
600 square foot limitation?
>> M
>> bothers me having two cars sitting
there,
>> Mr. Chair through you. Um I don't know
the exact measurements on that one.
>> Um
more than likely it could be like a 12
by It probably meets the 600, I should
say. Just based on kind of the width of
that driveway and the width of it, it's
more than likely meeting the 600. Okay.
I guess the other thing I found a little
confusing was when you wanted 50% of the
side covered, it doesn't matter where it
is on the side. I didn't quite
understand. So, M chair through you,
it'd be the upper um portion of the
carport. So,
kind of the example I would go with is
the one on the left. Um see how it kind
of angles the roof kind of comes down
onto the side a bit. Now, if you take
that side paneling and come down
It's about 50% of that side length.
That's what we're saying is you can kind
of enclose it on the sides down to that
50%.
>> So the one on the upper right wouldn't
necessarily meet the requirement. that
meets the other part of the standard um
that we have written in there which is
under G.
Um
uh as an alternative to the open facade
requirements above the lower 50% of an
enclosed uh side may be filled in with a
solid material provide the director
finds that the proposed enclosed
material finish color and detailing are
architecturally compatible with the
principal building.
>> Okay. So, we kind of threw that in there
because of ones like that. Um, where if
you architecturally integrate into your
house and make it look a lot nicer,
there's a little bit more of that
flexibility. And chair, members of the
commission, I just want to note that the
reason for the 50% being restricted to
the top for the metal carport buildings
is because if you start to add ones to
the bottom, then you have areas where
people can lean things against on the
inside and before you know it, it
becomes a collection. haven. So, um
that's why we limited to the top to to
actually let it function as a carport,
which is for the protection of the top
of your vehicles, not the bottom where
it could tempt you to continue to close
it in or attract clutter and such.
Any further questions for staff from the
commission?
>> Well, Mr. share just a comment from
Zoom. I'm actually kind of horrified to
see them out in front because the last
thing I want to see driving down the
streets of Cheyenne is carports down
every street, especially as they, you
know, get hard to see around. And I
mean, they're just ugly. But what other
municipalities even allow carports in
the front of the house? It's just very
surprising to me.
Um I believe that question was directed
to staff. So
>> chair, members of the of the commission,
Charles Bloom playing and development
director, we didn't take a deep dive in
this. This was again a council member
initiated um change based on a a
constituent that had made a complaint um
and had some concerns with how to uh
construct a carport. Um, I'm not aware
of any
any regulations um that would allow this
in these contexts that are illustrated.
Um, there could be the context of uh
zero lot line developments or alley
loaded carports that are just off the
alley. Those do exist other communities.
Um, but when you have a I'm not a I'm
not aware nor have we researched um ones
where you are allowed to have a carport
that essentially encroaches into a
required front setback, but we didn't
look for it.
>> I just see this I guess Mr. Chairman
where I'm coming from, I see this as
lowering property values. I
uh
I I don't know. We can't have them in
the front of houses in my opinion. And I
see them as lowering property values.
Make your you and your neighbor get into
it. They just throw up a big ugly
carport in front of your house. I mean,
or you go to sell your house and one of
them pops up overnight. Then what do you
sell your house for? I guess the the
front having them in the front of the
house is just a deal breaker for me on
this.
here. Members of of the commission, if I
may, just I want to correct something
really quick or just something.
>> Director Bloom. And I I guess
Commissioner, is there a question in
there for staff to respond to?
>> That's all right. Never mind. I can
>> Yeah. How did How did they study how it
affects property values, I guess?
>> Okay. Chair, I just wanted to provide
some clarification on how the assessor
sets um property values. Um, property
values in Wyoming are based off of
construction value of a property and
then they're weighted on um, condition
of the property. A brand new structure,
a house, accessory building, you will be
assessed on that at a high quality
structure um, based on and also concrete
if you put concrete down based on the
time from which it was installed. Um,
after that then it would decrease to a
level of good is what they call it which
lasts for a certain time period. again
is based on the square footage and the
rebuild value of that property not
aesthetics. Um then the uh the county
assessor is able to um do deviations
downward um after a certain time period
which um are based of on the condition
of the property and the um basically the
uh decrease in property
what is the right term um diminishment
of of the investment I'm not sure what
the right term is the Um
there's a there is a misnomer um across
the world of planning
where uses or changes in uses
lower property values when that's
typically not the case. Now it may be
accurate to say that a uh change in
regulation to allow something different
that might result in something
unattractive. It may not lower property
value per se, but it may decrease uh
aesthetics or property desiraability.
So, I just want to clarify it's not a
property value change. It would be a
property desiraability change which
could reduce um a sales price based on
desiraability.
So, I just want to provide that
clarification because we hear it a lot
with development proposals.
>> Okay. Thank you. I guess with that
response, Mr. Chairman, I when I look at
this, what I would like to see is uh if
they would like a carport out front is
something similar to how we allow
chickens at somebody's house. They have
to petition their neighbors and their
neighbors have to sign off on it because
I see this as affecting the entire
neighborhood and not just the property
owner. And when it's in your backyard,
you know, it's more secluded. When it's
inside your house, more secluded, but
when it's in your front yard, it is in
front and center for everybody. And so,
um, I would just like to see some
protection in place for everybody
surrounding these people.
>> Okay.
Thank you,
>> Mr. Chair. Three, you have a question.
>> Um, Commissioner Hernandez.
>> Yes.
>> So, kind of going off what Megan just
mentioned. Um, so
is there so somebody can just go out
there and just build a carport as along,
you know, as it goes through the
requirements of the sides, the top,
whatever. We're not there's not like a
a standard like we're not I mean they
can just build whatever or can they is
there actually going to be like it has
to be a certain it has to be metal it
has to be this it has to be you know is
there any kind of criteria
>> Mr. Chair through you so we don't have
any criteria in the zoning code they do
have to meet building code requirements
um so it can't just be I mean you can't
just put up
some random material that's not going to
have a snow load or anything like that.
Um, it's still going to have to meet
building code requirements, but we have
nothing that says it has to be metal or
it has to incorporate design elements of
the house or it has to be made of wood.
Um,
there's none of that within this
proposed text amendment. A lot of
building materials are going to be
probably dictated by building code. Uh,
what can support the snow load? uh what
can meet their requirements when it
comes to building code requirements.
Okay, thank you.
Any other further questions from the
commissioners who are on Zoom before I
start pestering the people on the dis.
Okay.
Uh Commissioner Leair, you indicated you
had a question for staff. Yes, Mr.
Chair, through you. I have a few, I
think. But, uh, first, Connor, you've
got several places in here where you
talk about a conditional use review, uh,
particular number of carports per
dwelling, uh, the height of the
principal building or exceeding the
princ height of the principal building,
um, and exceeding the 60 600 square
feet. I I'm thinking do you mean
variance or is that just a generic term
for going through the board for a
exception?
>> So, Mr. Chair, through you. Um
I don't know if we had anything come
before you while you were on the board
of adjustment. Uh but we actually did
kind of change the accessory building
code where you can actually instead of a
variant size and everything, we allow
conditional use. Now, the reason for
that is the conditional use looks more
at character the neighborhood. Does it
fit? can it meet these requirements kind
of rather than the strict you know how
strict the variance code could be I mean
if we had anything as a variance
I don't know probably nine times out of
10 it probably won't even make it
through um so with the conditional use
there's a little bit more of the
flexibility you still have to look does
it really match the neighborhood
um so say somebody did want two car
ports
maybe this in this neighborhood Nobody
else has a single carport or even has or
if they have a carport, they have one.
So why should you have two? Uh the
conditional use kind of looks at that.
What's the character of the
neighborhood? Does it make sense for
somebody else to have two now um in the
neighborhood? Um or if they want uh the
additional carport and they already have
a detached garage plus five sheds,
something crazy on the property, does it
really make sense? Um,
so that's why we have that in there for
conditional use. That's kind of
something we've looked at. When it comes
to kind of alternatives, it still goes
to the board of adjustment. It's just
instead of a variance, you're kind of
using the conditional use criteria.
>> Okay, Mr. Chair, that that's one
question and I appreciate that
clarification because I think they did
change that nomenclature.
Um,
so that picture in the upper right, I'm
still hung up on that, which appears to
me to be just an extension of the house.
I mean, I wouldn't call it an accessory
building of any kind. I I would call it
an extension of the house. Um, and it
seemed to me like when I was on the
board of adjustment, we did have a few
carports come to us in various uh
configurations that but one of the
things we seemed like we talked about
was if it were attached to the house
then it was considered part of the house
or an extension of the house which
triggered other requirements about
foundations and how it's secured to the
house and things like that.
um it was a little easier just to put up
a freestanding building, but then in
fact it is an accessory building and you
have to get into the setbacks like from
the side of the house and things like
that. Um
so I guess I'm I'm still stuck on that
that picture being a example of a
carport because I I don't I in my mind
that would not apply in this section at
all. that would no matter where it is in
the setback, it seems to me like it's
just part of the house.
>> And uh staff to follow up, I wanted to
ask if there would be a way to draft
this
that would be more tolerant of something
in the top right hand corner. Even if
the commission
is not on board with the other two
examples in the photograph
and chair, members of the commission,
Charles Bloom, planning the development
director, um several years back, we took
this very idea to you all um as part of
our unified development code annual
review and we also took it to the
governing body as a work session. the
governing and at that time the topic
specifically was to allow for carports
that were integrated in the house. That
was the the provision. They did not have
an appetite to move forward with that
and we did not receive any direction. Um
so we came back with a new appetite
which is this lesser design standard. Um
so that's what happened. So definitely
there are other
and again this is coming from one one
council member. I don't know what other
support would be there, but they are the
ones who are making this uh request. Um
I would like to note with that top right
picture that is very likely a conforming
structure, but picture the road 4t away
from that structure. That's when it
would be non-conforming because it would
be in that front setback. So that was
just used for an aesthetic example, not
a location example.
But I hope that um does clarify it. We
could
make amendments that could um
change the process to conditional use
for all of these elements where we do
look at appropriateness in the
neighborhood. Uh we could draft it as
is, keep it moving forward as is and let
the council make a decision or you could
um
make um a generalized recommendation to
the governing body that they consider a
change in the process to
require um like a conditional use
approval or some type of aesthetics. You
could postpone it as well.
>> And Mr. Sure. I'll just add for the one
that's in the upper kind of right.
I know that it's probably not the
typical type of cardboard you would look
at because it is integrated into the h
it's it looks like it is part of the
house. Um but ultimately all that
functions it's open on the entire 50%
top half over that wall. It's a carport.
Um it covers your vehicles. That's what
it's for. It's not a fully enclo
enclosed garage. So other than calling
it a carport, I'm not entirely sure what
you would call it, but it is a type of
carport. It's just it's integrated into
the house. It is the more aesthetically
pleasing type of carport, I would say,
where they they took the effort instead
of putting just a metal carport out
there. Um that is in the community. You
can actually find it right on ETH
Avenue. Um, if you drive down ETH by uh
Holiday Park,
um, or not Holiday, Lions, sorry.
I don't know why I was thinking Holiday,
but Lions Park. Um,
so that's that was more like uh,
Director Bloom said, that's I really
threw that in there as kind of that one
is conforming. It conforms with the 25
foot front setback already, but I want
to throw it in there as kind of an
example of that is something somebody
could do
in the other two photos.
They they could extend off the front of
their garage and make it look like part
of the house uh with this amendment. But
this amendment also allows what is in
the other two photos, metal carports on
front driveways. Um but yeah, just
mostly threw that picture in there is
kind of that is more of a probably
aesthetically pleasing version of what I
would consider a carport. Um that's
actually a photo that I used
back when I think we had a work session
with council as well and possibly even
with this planning commission, but that
was several years ago when we did that.
So as a followup to that then where it's
integrated into the house if a carport
is regulated as an accessory building
that would not be an accessory building
would it if it's actually part of the
building itself
>> correct and Mr. shared through use. So
then if if it's regulated under our
current code, um it would not be an
accessory building
uh if it's integrated and would become
part of the principal building, meaning
it needs a 25 ft front set back from the
front property line. Even if it's an
accessory is currently under code as an
accessory building and within 3 ft of
your house,
still needs to be 25 ft from the front
property line. Because if you remember,
we did change our accessory building
code to any accessory building within 3
ft of another structure becomes part of
that structure for setbacks. So if it's
within 3 ft of the house, it now needs
to meet your house's setbacks.
So
yes, as as an accessory building under
current code, um or if it's integrated
into the house, it needs to meet the
house's setbacks.
With the new proposed code, if we
consider it a carport,
then it can be within that 2 ft of the
front property line. But again, it can't
be enclosed more than the 50% on the
sides. That's where we kind of prevent
somebody from extending their garage all
the way to the front property line
and have this enclosed structure all the
way out there that then becomes a tunnel
and as we had mentioned probably becomes
clutter.
I guess one last question has to do with
the sides is
was there any thought or discussion uh
in in preparing this of
you know we've got some design standards
worried worried about clutter but in my
mind
I assume the point of a carport is still
protection from hail
whether the hail is coming vertically
whether it's coming horizontally whether
Whether it's coming in a swirl
and and and
the two unsightly carports I I assume
don't offer much protection from hail
with wind. Just as long as there's no
wind with the hail that they're okay. Is
that fair,
Mr. Chair through you? Uh, that could be
fair to say, but also with being able to
even cover 50% of the sides, I believe
that still covers a majority of the side
of your vehicle, at least the important
parts such as glass.
Um,
even if it's coming sideways, it's
probably you're might not cover the
entire car. So, yes, your tires and
maybe the lower half of your car is
potentially getting hit by the hell, but
it's still protecting the glass.
>> Okay, thank you. Any other questions
from the commission for staff before we
open it up for public comment?
Commissioner Lair.
>> Mr. Chair through you. And this is just
kind of a big picture planning theory
question. So what is the purpose of
setbacks particularly front and side
street setbacks? Is it purely aesthetic?
Is there any functional reason to have
those?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Um
generally it is has to do with
aesthetics. Um cuz there's even talking
with Seth when he went to San Francisco,
you have a driveway into your
front-loaded garage that's 5 ft before
you hit the garage. So they seem to have
a lot closer setbacks on their
residential structures in San Francisco
than we allow here with our 25 foot
front setback. So setbacks are mostly
their their aesthetics. Um it's how do
you want your streetscape to look? Do
you want it to be inviting? you want it
to be more open. That's why when you get
into some areas um like our I guess a
good example is our NR zones, those all
require rear loaded garages. Again,
that's so you don't have front-loaded
garages. Your front of the house is more
aesthetically kind of upfront to have
porches to have those connections
to basically make the make the
streetscape more aesthetically pleasing.
So I would say when it comes to
setbacks, it is it's about aesthetics at
least in the front. When it comes to
side setbacks, that can get a lot into
fire code, building code things where
you want to have structures be a certain
distance from property lines on the side
so you're not burning down your
neighbor's house uh if your house
catches on fire. Um and then rear
setbacks, uh our department's looked
into a lot. Do we need rear setbacks any
longer? Do rear setbacks really matter
when it comes to the rear of the
property?
The front I would say it's mostly it's
it's the streetscape. It is aesthetics.
>> Commissioner Mth.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Mr. Chair, you um I kind of
like the idea of having at least a
two-foot setback. I think of kids riding
their bikes down the the sidewalk
running into the pole of of the carport
and at least two feet would be some
measure of safety for the kids. And even
for like running your snowblower or
something like that, you might want to
keep the hole away from the sidewalk.
Any other questions for staff? questions
from uh commissioners on Zoom.
Okay, with that I'll open this up for
public comment. Are there any members of
the public present or on Zoom who wish
to speak?
>> And as a reminder, please use the raise
hand feature if you would like to speak.
>> Public comment going once, going twice.
Public comment is now closed.
And for the commission, I'm going to
take before I open this up for a a
motion, I am going to take issue with
Commissioner McFT.
I don't think two feet is anywhere near
adequate to protect us from what I'm
concerned about for pedestrians.
>> I agree, but I'm also trying to be
reasonable.
>> Okay. Is there is there a motion from
the commission?
I'm looking for a motion for us to
discuss.
Mr. Chair, I move to recommend the
governing body approve text amendment
text amendment to the unified
development code creating section 5.8.9
carports and amending section 1.4.3
defined terms and section 5.8.8
8 accessory buildings as outlined in the
staff report and recommended by staff
noting the amendments meet the review
criteria of UDC 2.4.1.D.
>> It's been moved by Commissioner
Hernandez. Do I have a second?
>> I will second that motion.
>> It's been seconded by Commissioner Trip.
discussion
or amendment by the commission.
Any commissioners worth want to speak?
>> Mr. Chair, I commissioner
>> move I am moved to make an amendment.
>> Okay.
>> I would like to change the definition of
a carport to read a carport functions to
offer limited overhead protection to
vehicles. Period. No, sorry. Limited
overhead protections to vehicles from
the elements. Period. The structure may
be a freestanding accessory building or
attached to another structure.
>> So, Mr. Chair, I just want to clarify.
So, we're striking. So, it's a carport
is used to offer limited protection. So,
basically striking and accessory
building,
>> right? My issue is based on what
Commissioner Wigum or Chairman Wigum was
talking about earlier. I think it's a
little contradictory that in some cases
it is an accessory building. In some
cases it's not based on whether it's
freestanding or attached. Yet the first
sentence flat out says it's an accessory
building and I don't think it is in the
case where it's attached. So I tempted
to take the accessory building part of
the definition put it in the second
sentence and just talk about the first
section is the function to provide
overhead protection.
>> Okay, it's been moved. Do we have a
second to Commissioner Lair's proposed
motion?
We have a second.
Could you reread it, please?
A carport functions to offer limited
overhead protection to vehicles from the
elements. Period. The structure may be a
freestanding accessory building or
attached to another structure.
Second.
>> It's been moved by
moved to amend by Commissioner Lair and
seconded by Commissioner Mate.
Any discussion of the proposed amendment
from the commission? Commissioners on
Zoom.
Comments, discussion
hearing. None. Staff please call RO on
the amendment.
Megan Connor,
>> yes.
>> Amy Hernandez,
>> Justin Trip,
>> yes.
>> Tony Lair,
>> I Mia,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Chair, that amendment passes.
>> Okay, thank you. We're back on the main
motion as amended.
Any other further discussion from the
commission?
>> Commissioner Lair.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. This isn't an
amendment yet, but I I also like the
idea of not letting that carport be
built right up against a sidewalk. And I
liked Chairman Wigs thought earlier
about maybe making a dimensional
um requirement having to do with the
distance of the carport from the
sidewalk, not necessarily from the
property line because obviously in many
of our properties the property line
already is several feet into a yard from
the sidewalk. So I don't know I don't
know that that the condition of the the
location of the property line is as
relevant as the sidewalk versus the
carport. And I'm not sure that two feet
is enough either, but I I'd like to see
what someone else has for an idea.
>> And Mr. Chair, if I may offer
suggestion.
Um,
so with something with kind of what
you're thinking, um, you could amend
it have to be an amendment, I think, to
probably C1 and C3
because one deals with the front
property line, the other deals with
corner lots.
Um, and where it states 2 feet from the
street facing property line and
you could state
5t from a sidewalk or 10 ft from a
sidewalk, whichever is
greater or I'm trying to remember if we
say greater or less. Um, whichever one
is more restrictive or something like
that. um to make it so that if a prop
basically if a property line is already
10 ft from a public sidewalk, they're
still required that 2 ft um potentially
unless the director can determine to
drop that to zero. They're still 10 ft
from the sidewalk. If the property
line's only 5t from the public sidewalk,
but you say it needs to be set back 10
feet, it has to be set back 10 feet. The
two feet from the property line doesn't
matter. Uh because that property line's
only 5t from the sidewalk.
So we could write that that could be
written in there so that it still
requires the two feet from a property
line but then also 10 feet from a public
sidewalk or five whatever the commission
determines is the best distance to be
from a public sidewalk. You could write
that in there as well kind of after the
two feet uh kind of line. So basically
adding it on to that. Um,
that would be my suggestion for
something along those lines so that you
still have both in there that but then
also you're making it so that if a
property line is greater than the
distance you're saying from the uh
the sidewalk, they still have to be that
2 feet as well from the property line.
Commissioner Lair, perhaps something
along I'm gonna tackle C1 here. Maybe
something that would read, uh, front
yard car port shall be set back a
minimum of two feet from the street
facing property line, comma, and also a
minimum of
10 ft from
any sidewalk.
Period.
which would mean that it would have to
meet both setbacks at least and maybe
something similar in C3.
Does that capture your thought?
It does. I I'm not sure if 10 feet's the
right distance either, but it's it's a
lot better than none or two feet.
>> That's for the commission to decide. 5
feet, 10 feet, 50 feet, three feet.
>> Mr. Chair, just just be careful on how
many feet you're doing because again,
the front setback for any home is 25 ft.
So, and if that property line is at the
back edge of sidewalk and you start
shrinking it, you're basically not
allowing them. Um, just something to
keep in mind as well.
Commissioner Mtha.
>> Well, I was just what what Hers just
said is what I was wondering is if we
were going to make it impossible to
build a a carport if we make it the
setback too far. I was thinking five
feet and I know you'd like more, but I'm
not certain.
>> What's the you know on on where you see
these things being put up? What's the
average setback that you're seeing?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Um, and
actually, Director Bloom just showed me
Colorado Springs actually does allow
them in their front yards. Um, they have
it at five feet from a sidewalk.
Um, and then they have at least 10 feet
from curb or roadway. So, they have kind
of a double there where five feet from
any sidewalk, but then also 10 feet from
any curb or roadway. But they do
actually in Colorado Springs allow them
in the front yard setback. So, that's
what they have. I don't again it's up to
the commission to go with uh to answer
commissioner uh's
question about what we kind of already
see it varies. Um it it really depends
on
how far the house is set back from its
front property line and where that front
property line sits. Is that front
property line adjacent to that detached
sidewalk or the attached sidewalk or is
it a number of feet off of those
sidewalks?
It varies throughout the community. So
if in some cases you have an attached
sidewalk and the property line is
adjacent to the back edge of that
sidewalk and the house is 25 ft, these
carports could be almost right at the
sidewalk in some cases. Um it it really
does vary. It's hard to really say what
we're seeing. Again, going back to
even the pictures. I mean, if you look
at the one that's on the left,
that is here in the community. That is
set
I don't know, 10, 15 feet from the
sidewalk maybe. Um, it is set quite far
back. It's not two feet from their front
property line. It's set further back,
but again, it's it's going to vary
depending on the situation.
So, but just want to throw that out
there with what Director Bloom found for
the for Colorado Springs. They have
theirs at the 5T.
Just as a general question though, is
there any chance that any of these were
installed legally either through a so
whatever the setback is? It's not
>> just whatever people decide to do. It's
wild west out there.
>> Mr. Chair through you. So I can again
the upper right hand corner one where
it's integrated in the house that when
that was built that actually meets
current setback requirements for the
house. So that one's fine. the metal
carports
under current code, neither one of those
are legal. Um,
they were just thrown on a driveway. I
don't even know if they have building
permits to be honest. Um, so
with the proposed code, the one on the
left, I could probably have a definite
say that it would become conforming and
legal.
The one on the bottom right is a lot
more questionable with how close it is.
Okay. Do we know if the car ports were
even
permissible for UDC such there such that
there might be some that are legal or
were legal when they were installed?
>> Mr. Pip,
>> Mr. Chair, through you. It I guess it
depends how they reviewed them preudc if
they were considered accessory buildings
or not. If they were accessory buildings
under pre uh preudc they would not have
been allowed because even under preudc I
think it was still your accessory
building couldn't be in your front yard.
But I can't speak for how planners
reviewed them because even in current
UDC we don't call carports out anywhere.
staff basically has just looked at
carports as being accessory buildings
and has reviewed them as such. That has
been staff's kind of directive on how to
review those.
>> And chair, members of the planning
commission, I just want to note real
quick a little bit of details on
Colorado Springs. Um it was adopted in
2021 after a council work session, lots
of discussion. It was a narrow vote,
four yes, three no. Um the primary
intent was for weather protection, very
similar to what is here. Um it is a
maximum of five uh feet from the
sidewalk, 10 feet from any curb line. So
if you have a a sidewalk or if you have
a detached sidewalk, it it changes. Um
also um the maximum size is 500 square
ft. It allows the metal looking ones
here provided the lower 60 in remains
open.
So didn't know about it, but we seem to
be pretty darn close to what they went
through. Um and their uh their policy
was driven on
and basically looking at the fact it
appears that a lot of people had been
building these without permits. Oh, and
it does clearly say they have to have a
building permit. Um but a lot of their
discussion in the articles I've seen
about it note that
there are a lot of non-compliance
structures that either had to a be
brought into compliance upon enforcement
action or they had to be removed.
Okay. Thank you. Further discussion. We
do not have any amendments. We we're
we're discussing the main motion. I
would offer that I totally agree with
Commissioner Connor that that the metal
car ports are ugly beyond belief.
I've got some in my neighborhood.
And I also used to sell hail insurance
and know what happens to people and
their vehicles and hail storms in
Cheyenne. And we know that we're going
to have one or two of big ones that are
going to total out cars again this
summer. So I I I get the desire as well.
But back to the issue of setbacks. Do we
want
I would say now is the time to offer an
amendment to change the setback language
if we want to do that. Otherwise, unless
there's some other point of
conversation, I'm going to head us
toward calling for a vote.
>> I would move we we make the setback five
feet
>> set back five feet from the sidewalk.
uh in addition to the two-foot proposed
setback or just a five-foot setback from
any sidewalk.
>> I would say five foot from any sidewalk.
>> Okay. And does this replace the language
that's in there now? Okay. So, for the
record, as I understand it, the motion
is to amend
5.8.9 8.9
C1 to read front yard carport shall be
set back a minimum uh of 5 ft from any
sidewalk.
What happens if there's not a sidewalk?
>> They go with the curb but
>> okay curb or sidewalk. Okay. And
>> oh 10 feet from the curb, five feet from
the sidewalk. settlement.
However,
sorry, five feet from the sidewalk and
10 ft from the curb if there is no
sidewalk.
>> Okay. And does that make sense? Can I
call for a second?
M
>> M Mr. Chair through you. I I I was going
to propose that amendment myself, but
I'm stuck on C3 because C3 is even more
confusing to me. But talking about the
direction the airport's oriented and all
those things, I I kind of like your
language about any uh sidewalk, which
would seem like cover both front
sidewalks and sidewise sidewalks at the
same time.
So, I'm looking for a second. Can I Can
I ask staff a question here? How does
Colorado Springs deal with carports on
the side?
Uh if if the motion that we're
contemplating seconding basically
mirrors Colorado Springs language
so Mr. share through you. Um, not
entirely sure if they talk about the
side kind of corner lot situation. It
probably might function the same as the
front, which is how we have it written
ultimately in ours. Um,
the only difference in C3 is you don't
get the two foot kind of from the side
property line. If
um you put the sidewall, the carport
facing the side property line. So if you
drove into the driveway and turned 90
degrees into the carport, you can't have
a carport that's the long way along your
side property line. It has to be for
vehicular access directly in is to get
the reduction. So that's why C3 is a
little bit longer than one. Um but
ultimately it's the same thing. It's
still allowing the two feet. So, I would
almost recommend that
um if you're going to make the amendment
to C1, make the same amendment to C3 and
just replace the two foot uh from a
street facing property line to the 5 ft
from any public sidewalk and 10 ft from
the curb.
Okay, we've got a motion. And it is your
motion just to C1 or do you want to
adopt the same language as suggested to
C3?
>> I would I would move that we apply.
>> Okay. And I don't have a second yet.
>> I second it.
>> Okay. It's been moved and seconded.
Any further discussion?
Commissioner Trip.
>> Yes, Chairman. My only concern putting
this language in there is each property
is different. So, if you have a short,
you know, I don't know. I have concerns
with putting five 5T in there just
because I don't want to limit a
homeowner from being able to put a
carport in there because it is his
property and as long as it's not
interfering with the sidewalk. So, I
just have concerns with putting that in
there.
Okay. Any further discussion?
Commissioner Leair.
>> Mr. Chair, just in the way of discussion
on the main motion. I I agree with what
>> um point of order. I think we're
discussing the the amendment. Then we
can talk about the main motion. Let's
stay on the amendment.
>> I withdraw my comment.
>> Any further discussion on the amendment
with different setbacks? Anything from
commissioners on Zoom
hearing? None. Will staff please call
roll
>> on the amendment.
>> Yes, I was going to clarify. We are on
the amendment. Uh Justin Trip,
>> no.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Yes.
>> Tony Lair. Hi.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> No.
Mr. Chair, that amendment does pass.
>> Okay. Thank you. We're back on the main
motion. Commissioner Leard, you had some
discussion.
>> My discussion just is that I I agreed a
lot with uh Commissioner Okconor or
Connor's
um comments earlier. I I'm going to vote
no on the main motion. I just think
aesthetically for our community and u
this allowing these carports in the
front is not good. Whether people have
been building them or not, they
shouldn't be and they shouldn't
continue.
>> Any further discussion? Commissioner
Trip,
>> thank you. Um I think I go back to
property rights. If a owner wants to put
one up there, I I have concerns. I may
not agree with what it looks like, but
it's their property. Um, so I would
support this based on that. And also I I
just think, you know, there's been some
examples with Colorado Springs. There is
weather protection issues out there. Not
everybody has a garage. Not everybody
can afford to extend from their property
either. So that's my thoughts on it.
>> Any further discussion?
I I'd just kind of to this discussion
part of it is the setback. I echoing
Commissioner Connor's comments.
Even if we do permit
carports, I'm not convinced that they're
necessarily appropriate for every
property. That there still needs to be
space for people to circulate and walk
around and, you know, not shade the
sidewalk all winter long so it stays icy
and those kind of things. Uh, secondly,
I do think that as ugly as they are, I'm
going to reiterate, there's nobody in
nobody in North America that I know of
that gets more hail than Cheyenne
Wyoming.
So, with that,
will staff please call Wolf
and we are on the main motion.
>> Tony Lair.
>> No. Before we go for a vote, could you
read the the motion again now as it's or
as a the proposal as it's now written?
>> I can I can mention how it's um written.
So this is um this is moving to approve
the text amendment as proposed by staff,
but it is amended so that the definition
for carports is a carport functions to
offer um
protection
Let me go back. Airport uh functions to
offer limited protection to vehicles
from the elements. The structure may be
freestanding or attached to another
structure. and then also amends
C.1 and C uh.3
so that those read
front yard carports shall be set back a
minimum of 5T from any public sidewalk
and 10 ft from the curb.
And then same thing with uh C3 on corner
lots where carports take direct direct
vehicular access from the side street
through the narrow dimension of the
carport. The side setback sh from the
street facing side property line shall
be reduced from or reduced to
uh 5t from any public sidewalk and 10 ft
from the curb.
>> Can I ask a quick question? I know I
called for a vote with the amendment we
just made to the setbacks.
Is there any scenario in which the way
we have it written would permit the
carport to be built within the public
right away or are we safe with those two
constraints?
>> Mr. Chair, I would say we're still safe
because you can't build a structure
within the public right of way. So,
>> okay, we've got that covered.
>> No matter what, they will have to be on
the property. Now, if they're at zero
ft,
that might allow them to be at zero feet
potentially, but to their property line,
not to the sidewalk. You still got to be
the distance from the sidewalk as you've
amended it, but um there's in no way can
you have a carport in the right way.
>> I just want to make sure. Thank you.
Please call roll. Okay, so again, we are
on the main motion. Tony Lair,
>> no.
>> Justin Trip,
>> yes.
>> Bob Matio,
Megan Connor,
>> no.
>> Amy Hernandez,
>> yes.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Other business, staff announcements and
chair, members of the commission,
Charles Bloom, planning and development
director. Um at the last meeting of the
regular last regular meeting of the
governing body, there is a moratorum
ordinance that was introduced and
referred to public service committee
regarding the construction of any uh
data centers or advancing any
development of a data center that
doesn't presently have a shovel in the
ground right now. So if you have an
approved building permit but aren't
digging, the proposal would essentially
halt those in their tracks. I would note
that this would not apply to an
annexation of um lands that are just
being zoned a blanket zoning because
that could be any use. Um it's not
necessarily a data center if it's zone
business park or industrial or light
industrial. It is just a blanket zoning
that could be anything from a tow truck
yard to a data center. So there's a
variety of folks there. Um that item was
considered after a lengthy three and a
half hour discussion at public services
committee which we for a second thought
it might overlap into this meeting at
the rate it was going um where it came
out with no recommendation. Um, so it
will be considered by the governing body
next Monday, uh, next Tuesday. Sorry, no
one will be here on Monday, thank
goodness. It's Memorial Day holiday. Um,
but it will be considered at 6:00 on
Tuesday um by the entirety of the
governing body where it will either be
um approved on second reading and
referred back to committee for
consideration and then final reading at
a subsequent meeting in June, the first
meeting for council in June. or it could
just be uh denied on
uh Tuesday which would end that
moratorum um discussion. A lot of folks
uh came to speak um in favor of it and
against it um including uh
local citizens against it. Lots of folks
against it. Lots of uh folks from local
unions and also from uh uh data center
developers and economic development
groups and state economic um development
representatives were here to speak in uh
against the moratorum. So that was
that's one major item that's been
happening um in our department. Uh we do
have a handful of items a pretty
significantly large agenda that's going
to be moving forward in June. So,
apologies in advance for another longer
meeting. Um, some of those are
annexation uh related with pretty large
uh land areas and uh business park or
industrial zone districts that are
associated with them as well.
>> And Mr. Chair, if I can add just just to
clarify for the commission, there are 12
items on that agenda. So, it it's going
to be a long agenda. Um
hopefully the meeting can run smoothly
and we can get through items
um at a decent pace but just be prepared
for a long long meeting.
And here the one final item I have to
note is that this Saturday right over
there in the library parking lot uh
there will be a safe uh streets um like
bicycle event from 10:00 to 1:00 where
there will be a group putting together
activities for kids to promote bicycle
safety. Um there could be some bicycle
helmets that will be handed out. I
believe there might be. And then at
noon, there will be a slow roll, which
is a bicycle event for all ages that
will uh take folks on a tour around the
neighborhood around here. They're
generally a a couple miles long, but
they're great family activities. So
again, this event's from 10:00 to 1:00
in the library parking lot. Um the
active transportation advisory committee
is partnering up with the Greenway
Foundation, which is partnering up with
another group that's hosting it. those a
bunch of community folks. And then
there's a slow roll at noon, which is if
you haven't been on the slow roll, they
do um do slow roll events every
Wednesday meeting at the Big Boy
starting at 6 PM and it starts on the
27th. It's truly a great time.
That's it.
>> I just had one question. Excuse me, Mr.
Chairman.
>> Have we cleared up all of the county
patchworks in the city except for that
farm? chair, members of the planning
commission. No. Um that last annexation
piece actually had 10 county pockets
that were about 14 or 17 individual
properties, give or take a few. Um that
is presently postponed until that
November 9th uh first meeting in
November of the governing body, which
means it'll go to committee that first
Monday of November. I believe it's
November 2nd.
Um, quick question. You mentioned the
the safe routes event. Did I see that
the MO is currently soliciting public
comment on the safe routes to school
that was somehow related to or was it or
was it something else entirely with the
recent
um plats that we've that we've dealt
with adjacent schools?
Chair, it is uh the NO is presently
working on their safe streets for all
comprehensive safety action plan that
was funded with a federal grant. They
will be present at this event on
Saturday as well. Um but they are um
also taking public comment on the draft
plan through June 5th of 2026.
Um, if you were to go to planchyen.org
and just save
streets,
we can email you out the link. It's
plans.orgsafe
streets 4-all
will get you there. And there's a public
feedback uh request based on the draft
plan. Okay. But that's not school
specific. That's that's communitywide.
Chair for you. This is that is more than
school specific. It's communitywide.
>> Thank you.
>> Anything else?
I'll accept a motion to adjurnn.
>> So moved.
>> We adjourned.